Josué Araújo

Montreal, QC, Canada

② josuearaujo.github.io ☑ engjosuearaujo@gmail.com ? josuearaujo **in** araujo-josue **4** 438-530-7406

Computer Engineer and an enthusiast in web development with work experience in PHP/Laravel and React. I am conditioned and highly prone to learning new tools and challenge myself to deliver the best results.

EXPERIENCE

Lightspeed Commerce

Montreal, QC, Canada

Software Developer

Sept 2021 - Mar 2023 (1y 6m)

- o Build internal tools and integrations for the Support Operations department.
- o Create usage documentation for users as well as technical documentation regarding implementations.
- Perform code reviews.
- Configure CI/CD deployment scripts
- o Participate in discussions to define product improvements and requirements.
- Analyze the feasibility and difficulty of the tasks.
- o Tech stack: PHP/Laravel, React, Node.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Git, Jira, Forge.

ESIG Software e Consultoria em TI

Natal, RN, Brazil

Software Developer

Apr 2019 - Oct 2020 (1y 7m)

- Implement new features and make corrections to systems.
- Prototyping and developing new interfaces.
- Actively participate in product innovation discussions, requirements analysis and feasibility studies.
- Perform code reviews.
- o Tech stack: PHP/Laravel, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Git, Scrum, Jira, Jenkins.

TRE-RN Tribunal Regional Eleitoral do RN

Natal, RN, Brazil

Database Admin/DevOps

Apr 2018 - Apr 2019 (1y 1m)

Feb 2017 - Dec 2017 (11m)

- o Create and maintain Docker images for systems deployments
- Prepare deployment scripts
- o Generate reports through SQL queries in the TRE databases
- o Provide help to internal and eventually external customers, providing support for understanding the solutions
- Monitor the organization of the TRE's servers infrastructure

UFRN Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte

Natal, RN, Brazil

Programming Language Teach Assistance

- o Language used: C++
- Help students in practices
- Make code corrections
- Assist the teacher in classes
- Teach exercise class

EDUCATION

UFRN - Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte

Natal, Brazil 2017- 2019

B. Sc., Computer Engineering

Natal, Brazil

UFRN - Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte B. Sc., Sciences and Technology

2014 - 2017

IFRN - Federal Institute of Rio Grande do Norte

Natal, Brazil

Mechanical Tecnician

2010 - 2014

CERTIFICATES & COURSES

Udemy

- o The Git & Github Bootcamp Apr 2021
- $\circ\,$ The Complete Guide 2023 (incl. React Router & Redux) Jun 2023

SKILLS

- o PHP
- Laravel
- o Node
- o React
- Javascript
- Typescript
- o HTML
- o CSS
- o Relational Databases
- o Agile
- o Git
- o Jira

LANGUAGES

- o Portuguese Native
- o English Full professional proficiency
- French Professional working proficiency